Guide to the National Council of Jewish Women, Pittsburgh Section Records, 1894-2011 AIS.1964.40
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Photographs, 1970-1989; XXIV.
  - Central District, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 25)
  - Oral History, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 26)
  - HIPPY, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 27)
  - Annual Meeting, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 28)
  - Ship-A-Box, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 29)
  - Designer Dress Days, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 30)
  - Washington Institute, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 31)
  - Central District, Omaha, 1988 (Box 76, Folder 32)
  - Opening Program Meeting, September 30, 1988 (Box 76, Folder 33)
  - Engineering Leadership, 1988 (Box 76, Folder 34)
  - Annual Meeting, 1988 (Box 76, Folder 35)
  - Council Care (Box 76, Folder 36-37)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 76, Folder 38-45)
- Organizational Records, 1956-1994; XXV.
  Series XXV contain organizational records of the NCJW Pittsburgh Section added in 1998. Much like the other series that contain organizational records, these materials relate to the Pittsburgh Section's activities and programs. There are some photographs contained in this series. Folders with photographs in them are labeled.
  - News releases, 1956 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - The Council Lounge, 1956, 1961-1962 (Box 77, Folder 2-3)
  - Yearbook, 1958-1959 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Angel Ball Publicity, 1957-1958 (Box 77, Folder 5-6)
  - The Bulletin, Volume 40, Number 4, May 26, 1959 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Council Woman, 1952-1955 (intermittent) (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - "Years of Progress" (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Public relations, 1962 (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - "67 Years Young", 1961 (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Lillian A. Friedberg radio broadcast, 1962 (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Gertrude Roth biography (Box 77, Folder 13)
  - Joel Greenwald biography (Box 77, Folder 14)
  - Mrs. Ronald Goldsmith biography (Box 77, Folder 15)
  - Council Thrift Shop, fashions by Saks Fifth Avenue, 1961 (Box 77, Folder 16)
  - Luncheon and Fashion Show, 1961-1962 (Box 77, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1963 (Box 77, Folder 18)
  - Stay-At-Home Ball (photographs), 1973 (Box 77, Folder 19)
  - Designer Dress Days, 1974 (Box 77, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, 1970s (Box 77, Folder 21-22)
  - Council Boutique, 1970 (Box 77, Folder 23)
  - Awards, 1980s (Box 77, Folder 24-25)
  - Soviet Jewry Plea (photographs), 1975 (Box 77, Folder 26)
  - Newsletter (Box 77, Folder 27)
  - Self-development Series (Box 77, Folder 28)
  - Hebrew University High School Project (Box 77, Folder 29)
  - Research Institute for Innovation in Education at the Hebrew University in Jerusalem, August 5, 1982 (Box 77, Folder 30)
  - National Committee on Public Relations (Box 77, Folder 31)
  - National Nominating Committee (Box 77, Folder 32)
  - 3rd Summit Conference in Israel, November 1978 (Box 77, Folder 33)
  - National public relations releases, 1984-1994 (Box 77, Folder 34-35)
  - Audio-visual material (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - "The Power of Excellence" (VHS tape), 1.
    - "Community Perspectives" (audio cassette), October 12, 1975; 2.
    - "The 1,000 Hour Day" (35 mm film), 3.
  - National Correspondence, 1980-1992 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - National Affairs Community Services Committee Newsletter (NACS), 1979-1988 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - NCJW by-laws, 1982-1992 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - NCJW National Board, 1987-1990 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - NCJW National Board, Pittsburgh Section, 1967-1990 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Action Alerts, 1975-1992 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Large/Large President's meetings, 1979-1993 (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Large/Large President's meetings, 1991-1992 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - National Nominating Committee, 1988-1992 (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - NCJW Centers for Women and Children, 1984-1992 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - National Membership Marketing Project, 1991 (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - National Section Fundraising Committee, 1983-1988 (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Executive Directors report, 1982, 1984 (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - National Field Service Committee Member's Kit, 1981-1983 (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - Headquarters funding, 1988 (Box 78, Folder 15)
  - International Council of Jewish Women, 1972-1987 (Box 78, Folder 16)
  - Like Size Section Commission, 1991-1992 (Box 78, Folder 17)
  - Staff meetings, 1991 (Box 78, Folder 18)
  - NCJW United Nations report, 1992 (Box 78, Folder 19)
  - Letters from National President, Joan Bronk, 1990-1992 (Box 78, Folder 20)
  - National Section services, 1992-1993 (Box 78, Folder 21)
  - National structure changes, 1990 (Box 78, Folder 22)
  - Women's Center, 1989, 1992 (Box 78, Folder 23)
  - Work/Family Project, 1992 (Box 78, Folder 24)
  - NCJW Public Affairs Manual, 1989-1990 (Box 78, Folder 25)
  - Action Update, 1991-1992 (Box 78, Folder 26)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1990, 1992 (Box 78, Folder 27)
  - Domestic violence hotline, 1990 (Box 78, Folder 28)
  - Environment and Energy, 1978, 1992 (Box 78, Folder 29)
  - Family and Medical Leave Bill, 1990-1991 (Box 78, Folder 30)
  - Shirley Lavine Memorial Lecture Series, 1988-1994 (Box 78, Folder 31)
  - Ilene Cohen Leefer, 1991-1992 (Box 78, Folder 32)
  - UJF, NCJW, Hadassah Legal Issues for Women, 1992 (Box 78, Folder 33)
  - Pay equity, 1990 (Box 78, Folder 34)
  - Israel affairs, 1991-1992 (Box 78, Folder 35)
  - Enriched Housing for Seniors, 1993 (Box 78, Folder 36)
  - Task Force Care for the Elderly, 1990-1992 (Box 78, Folder 37)
  - Task Force Residential Care for the Elderly, 1990-1993 (Box 78, Folder 38)
  - Ship-A-Box, 1981-1993 (Box 78, Folder 39)
  - Task Force on Aging, 1991 (Box 78, Folder 40)
  - Survey and evaluation, 1990-1991 (Box 78, Folder 41-42)
  - Young Associates, 1984-1999 (Box 78, Folder 43)
  - New American Resettlement Referral Line, 1990-1991 (Box 78, Folder 44)
  - Court Appointed Special Advocate Program (CASA), 1993 (Box 78, Folder 45)
  - Council Care Adult Day Care Program financial statements, 1991 (Box 78, Folder 46)
  - Juvenile Justice Award (includes photographs), 1990 (Box 78, Folder 47)
  - Women's History Month award, 1993 (Box 78, Folder 48)
  - Community services, 1991-1992 (Box 78, Folder 49)
  - Anathan House maintenance, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 50)
  - Children's Waiting Room, 1990-1993 (Box 78, Folder 51)
  - Joint Program with UJF, LHAS, and Hadassah, 1993 (Box 78, Folder 52)
  - Anathan House Cultural Center, 1990 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Anathan House Personnel, 1990 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Open Meeting, 1991 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Joint Program Meeting, 1990 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - LHAS/NCJW Joint Meeting, 1990-1992 (Box 79, Folder 5-7)
  - Annual Meeting (including photographs), 1993 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Council Care Adult Day Care Final Report, 1987 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Patient Advocacy for Pregnant Teens (PAPTE), 1992 (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - New American Women's Group (includes photographs), 1991 (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - New Americans, 1993 (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - New Project Development, 1993 (Box 79, Folder 13)
  - Council Care, St. Clair Hospital, 1990-1992 (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - Children's Waiting Rooms (includes photographs), 1990-1993 (Box 79, Folder 15)
  - Children's Waiting Rooms, Law Division, 1993 (Box 79, Folder 16)
  - Open Meeting, 1992-1993 (Box 79, Folder 17-18)
  - Distinguished Daughters of Pennsylvania, 1978-1986 (Box 79, Folder 19)
  - Leadership Development Course, 1990 (Box 79, Folder 20)
  - Personnel Practices, 1978-1991 (Box 79, Folder 21)
  - Revised by-laws, 1980-1990 (Box 79, Folder 22)
  - Annual Meeting, 1982 (Box 79, Folder 23)
  - Leadership Development Course evaluations, 1990 (Box 79, Folder 24)
  - Policies and procedures, 1981-1992 (Box 79, Folder 25)
  - Strategic Planning II, 1994-1995 (Box 79, Folder 26)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, 1980-1991 (Box 79, Folder 27)
  - Council Care survey and evaluations, 1990 (Box 79, Folder 28)
  - Survey and evaluation, 1990-1992 (Box 79, Folder 29)
  - Volunteerism Task Force, Long Range Planning, 1986-1987 (Box 79, Folder 30)
  - Fair Labor Standards Act, 1981, 1990, 1996 (Box 79, Folder 31)
  - Personnel policies and procedures, 1994, 1996 (Box 79, Folder 32)
  - Pittsburgh Foundation, 1984-1988 (Box 79, Folder 33)
  - Board training, 1993 (Box 79, Folder 34)
  - Board minutes, 1993 (Box 79, Folder 35)
  - Executive Committee, 1989-1994 (Box 79, Folder 36)
  - Board resignations, 1987, 1988, 1992 (Box 79, Folder 37)
  - Board lists, 1964-1965, 1984-1986 (Box 79, Folder 38)
  - Board training, 1993-1994 (Box 79, Folder 39)
  - Yeshiva Schools correspondence, 1989 (Box 79, Folder 40)
  - Nominating Committee, 1989-1993 (Box 79, Folder 41)
  - Russian wedding speeches, 1990-1992 (Box 79, Folder 42)
  - Vice Presidents meetings, 1990-1992 (Box 79, Folder 43)
  - Merrille Weissman, miscellaneous, 1991-1993 (Box 79, Folder 44)
  - Merrille Weissman, minutes and agendas, 1990-1993 (Box 80, Folder 1-2)
  - Merrille Weissman, Board letters, 1990-1993 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - HIPPY, 1990-1992, 1994-1995 (Box 80, Folder 4-5)
  - Council Care, 1983-1991 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Community Service information, 1991-1992 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Council Care, Lone Ranger, 1991-1992 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Ship-A-Box to Israel, 1988-1990 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Ship-A-Box, 1990-1992 (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Oral History Project, 1991-1992 (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Childcare, 1991-1992 (Box 80, Folder 12)
  - Student aid, 1990-1991 (Box 80, Folder 13)
  - Single Women in Midlife (SWIM), 1979-1990 (Box 80, Folder 14)
  - Russian Resettlement, 1981-1992 (Box 80, Folder 15)
  - Directory of Services and Facilities in the Jewish Community (Box 80, Folder 16)
  - Career Development Center (Box 80, Folder 17)
  - Russian Resettlement, Evaluations, 1989-1990 (Box 80, Folder 18)
  - Russian Resettlement, Arlene Shapiro, 1990 (Box 80, Folder 19)
  - Soviet Refugees Resettled in Pittsburgh, 1992-1993 (Box 80, Folder 20)
  - Resettlement Professionals, 1990 (Box 80, Folder 21-22)
  - Russian Resettlement, Recruitment General (Box 80, Folder 23)
  - Russian Mentors, 1990-1993 (Box 80, Folder 24-27)
  - Russian Resettlement, Mentor Family Program, 1990-1992 (Box 80, Folder 28-31)
  - The Challenge, 1991-1992 (Box 80, Folder 32)
  - Pro-Choice abortion, 1989-1993 (Box 80, Folder 33)
  - Pro-Choice, 1990 (Box 80, Folder 34)
  - Pro-Choice Bus March, Washington, D.C, 1989-1992 (Box 80, Folder 35)
  - Pro-Choice Bus March, Harrisburg, PA, 1989 (Box 80, Folder 36)
  - Anathan House-Community Gardens, 1988 (Box 80, Folder 37)
  - Pittsburgh Coordinating Committee of Jewish Organizations for Reproductive Freedom, 1990 (Box 80, Folder 38)
  - Nuclear Issue-Alliance for our Common Future, 1990 (Box 80, Folder 39)
  - Social Action, 1991-1993 (Box 80, Folder 40)
  - Pennsylvania State Public Affairs, 1990-1992 (Box 80, Folder 41)
  - Women's Health Issues, 1991-1992 (Box 80, Folder 42)
  - Women in Community Service (WICS), 1990 (Box 80, Folder 43)
  - Women's Resource Center proposal, 1990 (Box 80, Folder 44)
  - Women's Studies Program, University of Pittsburgh, 1990 (Box 80, Folder 45)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1977-1987 (Box 80, Folder 46)
- Membership and Volunteer Service, 1956-1993; XXVI.
  Series XVII includes many files pertaining to Council Care and other volunteer service programs, the Scholarship and Student Aid Committee, events held for new members, and recruitment and fundraising campaigns. Some minutes from meetings of the Executive Board, Advisory Committee, and the general membership are also found in this series. Several of the subjects in this series can also be found throughout the collection.
  - NCJW Mentor Family Program, 1992-1993 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Council Care (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Friends Indeed (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - New Americans Project (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Roy Hunt Foundation (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Speeches (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - General Information (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Scholarship and Student Aid Committee Minutes and Reports, 1968-1987 (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Evelyn Glauser Bernstein Grant (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - Comensky Scholarship (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Advisory Committee, General Membership, 1956-1959 (Box 81, Folder 11)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, 1964-1965 (Box 81, Folder 12)
  - Minutes: Advisory Committee, Agendas: Executive Board, 1960-1961 (Box 81, Folder 13)
  - "Fellows": Council Exchange Students (Box 81, Folder 14)
  - Head Start Program (Box 81, Folder 15)
  - Student Aid (Box 81, Folder 16)
  - Ship-A-Box, 1966-1974 (Box 81, Folder 17)
  - Department of Education and Political Action, 1962 (Box 81, Folder 18)
  - Arsenal Volunteer Service (Box 81, Folder 19)
  - Community Welfare Legislation Committee, 1955-1959 (Box 81, Folder 20)
  - "Council Gaieties", Peabody High School (Box 81, Folder 21)
  - Various Programs, Pamphlets, and Reports (Box 81, Folder 22)
  - Service to Foreign Born (Box 81, Folder 23)
  - Tutorial Program, U.P. Bethesda Community Center (Box 81, Folder 24)
  - Learning Disabilities (Box 81, Folder 25)
  - Public Affairs: Workshops (Box 81, Folder 26)
  - National and International Affairs (Box 81, Folder 27)
  - Lifestyle (Box 81, Folder 28)
  - Model Cities (Box 81, Folder 29)
  - Public Welfare Program/Welfare Reform (Box 81, Folder 30)
  - Israel: Projects (Box 81, Folder 31)
  - US Policy in Middle East (Box 81, Folder 32)
  - Pa. Human Relations Commission (Box 81, Folder 33)
  - Tax Reform (Box 81, Folder 34)
  - Pittsburgh Public School Reorganization (Box 81, Folder 35)
  - Public Affairs (Box 81, Folder 36)
  - School Lunch (Box 81, Folder 37)
  - National Standards on Women's Rights Groups (Box 81, Folder 38)
  - Local Affairs (Box 81, Folder 39)
  - Membership Retention, 1990-1993 (Box 81, Folder 40)
  - Membership Recruitment, 1990s (Box 81, Folder 41)
  - New Member Dinner, March 30, 1992 (Box 81, Folder 42)
  - New Members' Luncheon, February 22, 1990, March 13, 1991 (Box 81, Folder 43)
  - New Members' Telethon, October 12, 1989 (Box 81, Folder 44)
  - New Members' Functions, 1979-1983, 1987-1988 (Box 81, Folder 45)
  - Volunteerism (Box 81, Folder 46)
  - Telethons, 1988-1989 (Box 81, Folder 47)
  - Spa Trip, November 4, 1991 (Box 81, Folder 48)
  - South Hills, 1992 (Box 81, Folder 49)
  - Per Capita Forms, 1975-1990 (intermittent) (Box 81, Folder 50)
  - Membership Questionnaire, August 1990 (Box 81, Folder 51)
  - Stay-At-Home Ball, 1991-1993 (Box 81, Folder 52-53)
  - Anathan House Rental Policy (Box 81, Folder 54)
  - Video (Box 81, Folder 55)
  - Anathan House Personal Care Home Proposal (Box 81, Folder 56)
  - Life Membership Events, 1980, 1982, 1985 (Box 81, Folder 57)
  - Volunteer Information for Chatham Advisory, 1977-1978 (Box 81, Folder 58)
  - Membership Blitz, 1988, 1991-1993 (Box 82, Folder 1-2)
  - Life Membership Event, 1991-1992 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Getting to Know You Committee, 1993 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Volunteerism, 1974-1978 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Membership Events, 1990-1991 (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Membership Department Reports, 1985-1993 (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Volunteering, 1992-1993 (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Pittsburgh Foundation Grant Requests, 1987-1988 (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - Adult Day Care Plan, 1987 (Box 82, Folder 10)
  - Council Care/St. Clair Hospital, 1987 (Box 82, Folder 11)
  - Council Care: Award Application, 1986-1987 (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - Council Care Advocacy (Box 82, Folder 13)
  - Council Care Publicity (Box 82, Folder 14)
  - Council Care Training (Gene Dickman, Management Board Chair), 1988-1989 (Box 82, Folder 15)
  - Council Care PR (Box 82, Folder 16)
  - Council Care Clippings (Box 82, Folder 17)
  - Council Care II Evaluation Report, December 1987 (Box 82, Folder 18)
  - Summary Report: Affective Disorders in Memory Impaired Adults Attending Day Care, 1988 (Box 82, Folder 19)
  - Council Care Centers: Volunteer Recognition, Grand Openings (Box 82, Folder 20)
  - Personnel Practices and Search Committee (Box 82, Folder 21)
  - Council Care Research Projects (Box 82, Folder 22)
  - Council Care, South Hills (Box 82, Folder 23)
  - Fitness Day, May 14, 1990 (Box 82, Folder 24)
  - Fox Chapel Outreach, November 29, 1989 (Box 82, Folder 25)
  - Directory, 1990-1993 (Box 82, Folder 26)
  - Student Aid Committee, 1957-1969, 1976-1984 (Box 82, Folder 27-28)
  - Scrapbooks, 1961-1983 (Box 82, Volume 1-3)
  - Posters and signs (Oversize 1)
- Photographs, 1990-2003; XXVII.
  Photographs in this series show organizational activities, including the Angel Ball, a Soviet wedding, and golf outings. Names of those pictured can be found on the back of the photographs. They are arranged chronologically within each activity.
  - RFTC Award (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Centennial (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - April 5, 1992 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Centennial Display Board, Photos Not Used (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Council Care, 1993 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Membership Blitz, 1991-1996 (Box 83, Folder 6-11)
  - Golf, 1990, 1996-2001 (Box 83, Folder 12-18)
  - Silent Witness, 1997, 2003 (Box 83, Folder 19-20)
  - Washington Institute (Box 83, Folder 21)
  - Young Women: Center for Creative Play, Derby Night, 2003 (Box 83, Folder 22)
  - Young Women: Beading at Lynne Garfunkel's Home, 2003 (Box 83, Folder 23)
  - Joan Levy Receiving Award, 2003 (Box 83, Folder 24)
  - WQED (Box 83, Folder 25)
  - Love Fore Kids, 2001 (Box 83, Folder 26)
  - Services to Elderly Committee, April 26, 2003 (Box 83, Folder 27)
  - Stay-At-Home Ball, 2003 (Box 83, Folder 28)
  - Designer Dress Days, 2002-2003 (Box 83, Folder 29-30)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 83, Folder 31)
  - Soviet Wedding, 1989 (Box 84)
  - Angel Ball Photo Album, 1966 (Box 85, Item 1)
  - Angel Ball Photo Album, undated (Box 85, Item 2)
  - Evening Division Scrapbook, 1961-1967 (Box 85, Item 3)
  - Evening Division Scrapbook, 1966-1975 (Box 85, Item 4)
  - Evening Division Scrapbook, 1976-1983 (Box 85, Item 5)
- NCJW Oral History Projects, 1967-2001; XXVIII.
  Series XVIII contains materials relating to three oral history projects conducted by NCJW between 1968 and 2001. Through the personal accounts of over 500 men and women from the Pittsburgh area, the projects document the immigration of European Jews to the region as well as many aspects of Jewish-American life in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries, including immigrant education, holidays and religious practices, reactions to World War I and World War II, family structures, and the lives of women. These gathered remembrances help preserve early social and political cultures while providing insight into the creation and history of the Pittsburgh community as a whole.
  The majority of the interviews were collected by the NCJW Pittsburgh Section through two systematic studies. The first, carried out between 1968 and 1969, focused specifically on the experiences of individuals who had immigrated to Western Pennsylvania between 1890 and 1924 - a time when thousands of persecuted Jews left Eastern Europe to seek new lives in the United States. Excerpts from the interviews formed the basis of By Myself I'm a Book!, published by the American Jewish Historical Society. The second project began in 1974 and took a broader approach, interviewing older members of the Jewish community regardless of background. This project continued through 2001, and some individuals were interviewed a second time to provide updates and evidence of change. The book My Voice was Heard was based on this set of interviews. Both projects are notable for their large scale and sociological methods; information on the methodology behind the first study may be found in the introduction to By Myself I'm a Book. Although many members of NCJW contributed to the projects, Gene Dickman and Marcia Frumerman chaired and supervised it in its entirety.
  In addition to the two project books, there have been a number of other publications and productions based on the Pittsburgh Section Oral History Project. "Bridges to History," a 26 minute film, features vignettes based on both projects and explains how the interviews were gathered. A 1985 pamphlet entitled Partners in Creation was used as a curriculum guide for the study of My Voice Was Heard. In 2002, abstracts for all interviews were collected into Pittsburgh and Beyond: The Experience of the Jewish Community. In 2009, the audio cassettes were digitized and mounted online for greater accessibility.
  The South Hills Branch of NCJW also conducted an oral history project, interviewing nineteen Jewish men and women living in the South Hills area of Pittsburgh between 1979 and 1983. The project focused on early experiences in Europe prior to emigration and adjustment to life in a predominantly non-Jewish community. This project is unrelated to the studies carried out by the Pittsburgh Section, and files are subject to different restrictions. Please contact the ASC for more information.
  The folders listed below contain information associated with the recorded interviews and include photos, transcripts, notes, and biographical information supplied by the interviewer and interviewee. The interviews have been reformatted from audio cassettes to MP3s and are available for streaming online through the Pittsburgh and Beyond website.
  In 2011, NCJW Oral History Project Co-Chairs Marcia Frumerman and Marlene Haus donated to the archives additional material documenting the oral history projects. Files were added to the Pittsburgh Section Project I: The Immigrant Experience and Pittsburgh Section Project II: My Voice was Heard. The new material has been added at the end of each existing subseries. Four new subseries (Advisory Committee; Oral History Course Curriculum Development; Abstract and Index Project; and Volunteer Interviewers Training Materials) were added to the series. Further scope notes are found after each subseries title.
  - Pittsburgh Section Project I: The Immigrant Experience, 1.
    This subseries contains the first set of interviews conducted by the NCJW Pittsburgh Section. Since the goal was to document how early Jewish immigrants adjusted to life in Pittsburgh, respondents were confined to foreign-born citizens who had immigrated to Western Pennsylvania between 1890 and 1924. Interviews focus on topics such as ancestry, overseas life, departure, journey, and Americanization and assimilation. Material added in 2011 can be found under the section "New Material Added."
    - History of the Project, 1986 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Pilot Study, Instructions, 1968 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Pilot Study, List of Interviews, 1968 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Pilot Study, Pilot Tape, 1968 (Box 86, Folder 3.1)
    - Development of Questionnaire, Report, 1968-1969 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Development of Questionnaire, Four Versions, 1968-1969 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Interviewing Technique, 1968-1970 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Interviewers and Respondents, Lists of Interviewers (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Interviewers and Respondents, Lists of Respondents (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Abrams, Israel, undated (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Adler, George, January 10, 1969 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Amdur, Sam, undated (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Americus, Ida, February 10, 1969 (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Arenson, Bella, January 12, 1969 (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - Arenson, Louis, January 12, 1969 (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - Arluck, Goldie, undated (Box 86, Folder 15)
    - Arluck, Norman, undated (Box 86, Folder 16)
    - Aussenberg, Elias, undated (Box 86, Folder 17)
    - Berland, Lucille, undated (Box 86, Folder 18)
    - Bernstein, Dora, November 23, 1968 (Box 86, Folder 19)
    - Bigler, Sam, December 1, 1968 (Box 86, Folder 20)
    - Blatt, Ida, undated (Box 86, Folder 21)
    - Blitz, Esther, November 4, 1968 (Box 86, Folder 22)
    - Bloch, Minnie, undated (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Blum, Hyman, undated (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Blum, Lisa, undated (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Bodek, Max, 1969 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Boodman, Sam, May 20, 1969 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Borkon, Louis Yale, 1969 (Box 87, Folder 6)